SUBHAJIT DAS

8961219163 | subhajit.das@iiitb.net | Kolkata

PROFILE SUMMARY

Over four years of experience in analysis, design, development of predictive analytical models with an expertise in R, Python and SQL. Deep understanding of technology with a demonstrated ability to deliver valuable insights via analytics and advanced machine learning algorithms using R and Python.

ACADEMIC CREDENTIALS

PG Diploma in Data Science I CGPA 3.52/ 4
...

Year- 2018

IIIT-Bangalore

B. Tech, Electronics and Communication Engineering I CGPA 7.78/10

 Calvarian Calvarian Callage I West Page and University of Technology

Year- 2014

Kalyani Government Engineering College | West Bengal University of Technology, Kolkata

WORK EXPERIENCE

Current Organization: *Cognizant*, Associate Data Scientist, Kolkata June 2018 – Present

- Analysed the Hospital Care Professional (HCP) behaviours through Key Driving Factors (linear regression) with respect to
 actual sales of a drug. Increased growth on selling drug revenue by leveraging HCP's acquisitions and improved physician
 marketing strategies through Segmenting them according to their drug Prescribing pattern using K-Means clustering
 algorithm and Developed a propensity score using advanced machine learning algorithm (Logistic Regression, Random
 Forest) for each HCP's which will devise a successful go to market strategy.
- SAS to R migration of different protocols like 'Logit-Log' is a calculation method for quantification of antigenic mass by Elisa, based on logit log transformation and linear regression and Visualize those using R Shiny.
- Underlying reasons behind patient absenteeism to visit HCP or clinic and **strategize** to improve the conversions rate. It is analysed through **'Compellon Causality Engine'** (Hackathon Winner).

Previous Organization: *Jardine Lloyd Thomson*, Business Analyst, Mumbai July 2017 - May 2018

- Developed and implemented a marketing strategy to optimize the marketing cost and achieve 80% of total responders at the minimum possible cost for the selling of an Investment product for a UK based multinational bank and target the one's, most likely to respond in the next telemarketing campaign using advanced analytical predictive models.
- Developed an attrition analytics framework that uses a predictive model to generate a score for each employee of leaving
 the organization using Logistic Regression & Random Forest and came up with top 3 reasons for Employee attrition to
 design an Early Warning System framework.
- Built a model using Support Vector Machine to identify the handwritten digits between 0 to 9 written in an image. (POC)

Previous Organization: *Accenture*, Analyst, Bangalore April 2015 - July 2017

- Forecasted the sales and the demand of an online store for its top two most profitable and consistent segment for the next six months, using auto ARIMA and consulted the strategy to manage the revenue and inventory accordingly.
- Evaluate a predictive model to identify the customers who are at the risk of cancelling their membership of a premium club boasts a large customer base, developed using supervised classification machine learning algorithms.
- Build the **portfolio of risk assessment** with an **exploratory data analysis** to find the key driving factors behind loan default and analysed the correlation between different variables using **Heatmap** and created dashboard using **Tableau**.

KEY SKILLS

- Machine Learning Modelling Techniques
- Visualization: Seaborn, Ggplot2, Tableau, RShiny
- Statistics & Hypothesis Testing
- DevOps- Jenkins, AWS, GitHub

- Wiley Certified Data Scientist (CZN-CDS-KOL-280119002)
- Analytics Languages: R, Python, SQL
- Databases: SQL Server 2008, MySQL
- •Big Data: SparkR, PySpark, Amazon S3, EMR Cluster

ACCOLADES

- Innovator and Responsible to execute a coherent plan of action and received a spot award from Delivery Unit lead.
- School level success in All India Mathematics Olympiad, National Talent Search Competition, National Science Olympiad.